<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Getting Started - Daily Paer</title><description>Thoughts, stories and ideas...</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.5</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 00:23:02 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/tag/getting-started/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Startup, but Don’t Drop Out</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Gates, Jobs, and Zuckerberg: the superheroes of every student with startup aspirations. Whether in high school or college, thousands of students check the news sites like TechCrunch and HackerNews daily, and read headlines of numerous startups being bought for millions and millions of dollars. Bored in class, these students dream about having a headline — and “stacks of cash” — of their own. Their idols and the media create the illusion that school is not a necessity, but rather an obstacle on the road to startup success and fame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/1200/1*6R4IdJXMrkeyijsKospU6w.jpeg" width="50%"&gt; No need for caption here... &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a senior in high school and the founder of Paer, I firmly believe that school is not just a necessity, but the best safety net a startup could have. I’m not just talking about having an education; I’m saying that running a startup while you’re still a student and in school is the safest way to run a startup, at least in its early stages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, roughly thirty students from my high school attended Hack Generation Y, an international hackathon in Palo Alto just for high school students. During the opening ceremony, a representative from a sponsor organization aiming to replace traditional 4 year college with their coding-focused program gave a talk to 400 eager-to-succeed high school students encouraging them that college was not only unnecessary, but in fact, a roadblock for achieving early success in life. His main point was that for young entrepreneurs and innovators, college did not offer enough helpful tools for success at the current cost of an education. A valid point, but it misses reality by a wide margin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure you might drop out of high school or college, make a startup, and become the next Bill Gates. But you can also drop out of school, make a startup, fail, and live your youth in your parent’s basement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/2000/1*oSdYWt1xTyIr5zBctEaLeQ.jpeg" width="80%"&gt; &lt;br&gt;
The Paer Team at HackGenY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We as humans tend to focus on the one blinding beacon of success rather than the thousands of silent failures that surround it, which is what made us uneasy when many high school students at the hackathon were eagerly nodding their heads in approval and whispering “yeah, this sounds better than college,” as the representative from the organization convinced them that a college education was inferior to running a startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’m not saying that the students from my high school were wiser than the rest of the students there. Coming from a prominent private school, many of us have the resources to comfortably attend college and graduate school, and from a young age, our parents have ingrained in us the value of higher education. I respect that the comparatively cheaper price of attending that organization’s program can be very attractive to an entrepreneurial-striving student who does not have the resources to comfortably attend college, or to one who comes from a low-resource public school, and does not think that our current education system is doing him or her justice. But what is often not realized is that the cost of school buys not only an education, but also the best safety net any startup could have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since founding Paer almost three weeks ago, my team and I have frequently asked, “what if we weren’t students?” The most common answers were “we could finish this app in no time,” which led to, “we’d be rich” or “we’d be famous,” but eventually we would sadly acknowledge the prospect of failure, and conclude how screwed we would be in the likely event of failure. What’s oddly beautiful about that last realization is it made us realize that as students running a startup, if we crash and burn miserably, guess what, we’re still students. And that’s why being a student is the best safety net anyone who is part of a startup could have. Because if you fail, so what? You keep hitting the books, maybe try again, or just join the workforce with startup experience on your résumé. Sure, development time will slow down and you’ll undoubtedly spend many sleepless nights having to balance the stress of academics with the pressure of running a startup, but by doing so, your cost of failure becomes almost negligible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;School isn’t just the best safety net; it can also be a wealth of “free” resources for your startups. In school, you have direct access to thousands who are willing to work for free or cheap, thousands who are ripe with new ideas, and hundreds of teachers with decades of experience that you (or your parents) are paying for to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During these last three weeks, I’ve met with my teachers to seek advice on patents, legal documents, design principles, and coding practices. And though “having fun” is a phrase that’s been phased-out in today’s startup culture, running a startup with your friends at school definitely keeps things fun and enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, your education is what you make of it. You can view school as an obstacle to early success and fame, and thus be bored by all the classes you’re “forced” to take. But you can also view school as an opportunity to explore your entrepreneurial interests risk-free, as a time to meet your co-founders for the next big thing, and as a time to be mentored by adults whose primary career goals are to teach. Be proactive. Take classes that interest you, that relate to your startup, or that relate to the itching new idea that you are trying to realize. Pay attention in class and study hard, because you never know when something your teacher says during that two-hour long lecture for an intro course sparks the idea that’ll make you billions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s why — despite coming from the same high school that once taught Bill Gates and Paul Allen — my team and I firmly stand by our belief that it is not just logical, but imperative that we run our startup and education parallel. True, it might not be the most efficient way to run a startup, but it sure is the safest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aneesh Sachdeva, Founder of Paer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/www.paer.io"&gt;Paer.IO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/2015/02/20/startup-but-dont-drop-out/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">f8eb475b-6ad5-4d7f-96ed-6098cfa645ca</guid><category>Getting Started</category><dc:creator>Paer</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 22:32:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>PubNub feature: Instant Data Transfer between mobile devices</title><description>&lt;p&gt;In 30 hours, a team of five high schoolers had prototyped their iOS application at the &lt;a href="http://hackgeny.com/"&gt;HackGenY&lt;/a&gt; hackathon earlier this month. The team’s goal was to transform the modern business card as simply as possible. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result is &lt;a href="http://paer.io/"&gt;Paer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.pubnub.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/paer_gif.gif" alt="Paer Demo"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paer is an iOS app that uses Bluetooth Low Energy Tech (BluetoothLE) to enable users to instantly exchange and transfer contact information and connect across numerous social platforms by simply touching phones. BLET is a faster and cheaper alternative to NFC, and the app essentially eliminates business cards by streamlining the process of networking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h6 id="youcaneasilypaerwithsimplesteps"&gt;You can easily paer with  simple steps&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create a personal profile with your information you wish to share  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;choose the social medias you want to use to connect with others  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;done! go out and paer!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;originally written by Joe Hanson, February 12, 2015. &lt;br&gt;
Follow him &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/ToeJamson"&gt;@ToeJamson&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See more at: &lt;a href="http://www.pubnub.com/blog/transfer-data-between-ios-devices-with-bluetooth-low-energy-tech/#sthash.JEPIBfV2.dpuf"&gt;http://www.pubnub.com/blog/transfer-data-between-ios-devices-with-bluetooth-low-energy-tech/#sthash.JEPIBfV2.dpuf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/2015/02/20/pubnub-feature-instant-data-transfer-between-mobile-devices/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">06d6acf6-08f9-4f1d-b4b0-7fd31abe6739</guid><category>Getting Started</category><category>Family</category><dc:creator>Paer</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 11:38:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Welcome to Ghost</title><description>&lt;p&gt;You're live! Nice. We've put together a little post to introduce you to the Ghost editor and get you started. You can manage your content by signing in to the admin area at &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;your blog URL&amp;gt;/ghost/&lt;/code&gt;. When you arrive, you can select this post from a list on the left and see a preview of it on the right. Click the little pencil icon at the top of the preview to edit this post and read the next section!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="gettingstarted"&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ghost uses something called Markdown for writing. Essentially, it's a shorthand way to manage your post formatting as you write!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing in Markdown is really easy. In the left hand panel of Ghost, you simply write as you normally would. Where appropriate, you can use &lt;em&gt;shortcuts&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;style&lt;/strong&gt; your content. For example, a list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item number one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item number two
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A nested item&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A final item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or with numbers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember to buy some milk  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drink the milk  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tweet that I remembered to buy the milk, and drank it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id="links"&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to link to a source? No problem. If you paste in a URL, like &lt;a href="http://ghost.org/"&gt;http://ghost.org&lt;/a&gt; - it'll automatically be linked up. But if you want to customise your anchor text, you can do that too! Here's a link to &lt;a href="http://ghost.org/"&gt;the Ghost website&lt;/a&gt;. Neat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="whataboutimages"&gt;What about Images?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Images work too! Already know the URL of the image you want to include in your article? Simply paste it in like this to make it show up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ghost.org/images/ghost.png" alt="The Ghost Logo"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure which image you want to use yet? That's ok too. Leave yourself a descriptive placeholder and keep writing. Come back later and drag and drop the image in to upload:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="quoting"&gt;Quoting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a link isn't enough, you want to quote someone on what they've said. It was probably very wisdomous. Is wisdomous a word? Find out in a future release when we introduce spellcheck! For now - it's definitely a word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Wisdomous - it's definitely a word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="workingwithcode"&gt;Working with Code&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got a streak of geek? We've got you covered there, too. You can write inline &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; blocks really easily with back ticks. Want to show off something more comprehensive? 4 spaces of indentation gets you there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.awesome-thing {
    display: block;
    width: 100%;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id="readyforabreak"&gt;Ready for a Break?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throw 3 or more dashes down on any new line and you've got yourself a fancy new divider. Aw yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id="advancedusage"&gt;Advanced Usage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's one fantastic secret about Markdown. If you want, you can write plain old HTML and it'll still work! Very flexible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;input type="text" placeholder="I'm an input field!"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That should be enough to get you started. Have fun - and let us know what you think :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/2015/02/19/welcome-to-ghost/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">9b3abb29-948e-4438-9248-9ca8b65baec8</guid><category>Getting Started</category><dc:creator>Paer</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 23:12:36 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>